<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Phil&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://philipdaniels.com/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Phil&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 20:19:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://philipdaniels.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Setup in Hyper-V and Virtual Box</title>
      <link>http://philipdaniels.com/blog/2016/vm-networking-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 20:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://philipdaniels.com/blog/2016/vm-networking-overview/</guid>
      <description>Other Build Book Posts  Debian VM Setup Setup of SSH Windows VM Setup  Posts in the Build Book sequence are intended primarily as an aide-mémoire for myself; a series of steps to go through for a consistent build experience. They tend to be to the point, prescriptive and tailored for me personally.
In this article I describe the different types of switch available in Hyper-V and their equivalents in Virtual Box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup of Debian Virtual Machines</title>
      <link>http://philipdaniels.com/blog/2016/debian-vm-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 20:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://philipdaniels.com/blog/2016/debian-vm-setup/</guid>
      <description>Other Build Book Posts  Setup of SSH Windows VM Setup Network Setup in Hyper-V and Virtual Box  Posts in the Build Book sequence are intended primarily as an aide-mémoire for myself; a series of steps to go through for a consistent build experience. They tend to be to the point, prescriptive and tailored for me personally.
Installation Steps Pick the type of Debian distribution you want. I usually go for Testing to keep up with the latest fixes - it is a rolling release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup of ssh</title>
      <link>http://philipdaniels.com/blog/2016/setup-of-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 20:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://philipdaniels.com/blog/2016/setup-of-ssh/</guid>
      <description>Other Build Book Posts  Debian VM Setup Windows VM Setup Network Setup in Hyper-V and Virtual Box  Posts in the Build Book sequence are intended primarily as an aide-mémoire for myself; a series of steps to go through for a consistent build experience. They tend to be to the point, prescriptive and tailored for me personally.
How SSH Works SSH stands for &amp;ldquo;Secure Shell&amp;rdquo;. As its name implies it is a network protocol for secure communication between two computers, a server - your VM - and a client, e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>